Guide to the Paul Nash Letters to Mercia Oakley
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Letters, Nash, Paul, 1889-1946
  - Letter to Mercia Oakley, 1914 December 10; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed: 20 x 25 cm (Box Nash 49)
    Written from Iver Heath. Nash invites Oakley to visit. Includes envelope. People mentioned: John Nash.
  - Letter to Mercia Oakley, between 1914 and 1918; 3 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed: 20 x 13 cm (Box Nash 50)
    Written from Denham. Nash hopes to see Oakley soon and adds that he has taken a commission and is stationed at Denham. He inquires after her honeymoon and expresses his hopes of becoming an officer, although he does not like war and feels he will never be a real soldier.
    World War, 1914-1918
  - Letter to Mercia Oakley, early 1918; 2 pages (1 leaf): autograph letter, signed: 27 x 21 cm (Box Nash 51)
    Written from Queen Alexandra Mansions. Nash has given a portrait of Oakley to Robert Nichols, who wishes to write a poem about it. Nash's wife is terrified of air raids.
    Nichols, Robert, 1893-1944; Nash, Margaret Theodosia, 1887-1960
- Miscellaneous
  - Envelope addressed to Mercia Oakley, 1912 August 24; Nash, Paul, 1889-1946; 10 x 12 cm (Box Nash 52)
    Postmarked Iver Heath. Bears ink drawing of a winged man (reproduced in Dear Mercia, p. 107).
    Pen and ink drawings; Oakley, Mercia
  - Photogravure of Lavengro and Isopel in the Dingle, circa 1913?; 1 photograph; 14 x 11 cm (Box Nash 53)
    The photograph reproduces Nash's Lavengro and Isopel in the Dingle (1912-1913), a drawing now in the collections of the Tate. See: http://www.tate.org.uk/art/artworks/nash-lavengro-and-isopel-in-the-dingle-t01782
    Photographs
  - Envelope addressed to Mrs. Grimsdale (Mercia Oakley), 1951 May 27; 28 x 22 cm (Box Nash 54)
    Oakley, Mercia